Gerrard Padilla

2379 Rosewood Court, Rochester, MN 55902 youremail@exarnple.com (123) 456-7891

Accomplished medical laboratory technician with over 10 years of experience and national certification with the American Society of Clinical Pathology. Receives top-rated evaluations almost every year and is known for optimistic outlook and commitment to outstanding accuracy rates. Current lab's go-to expert for questions about lab information systems and passionate about participating in community events and responding to crises,

Key Skills

- Detail Oriented
- Lab Safety
- OSHA Compliance
- Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, Outlook, Access, PowerPoint)
- Laboratory Information Systems (Sunquest, LabSoft, LabWare)
- Microscopic Image Capturing Software
- Phlebotomy
- Mentoring

Professional Experience

Senior Medical Laboratory Technician

Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN I October2019 - Present

- Perform blood and body fluid tests, cell and tissue cultures, and DNA/RNA extraction
- Maintain excellent supply and equipment inventory systems, which has helped reduce wait time for test results by 30% and eliminated the costs for last-minute orders
- Evaluated favorably for excellent accuracy, attitude, abilities, and willingness to go above and beyond
- Use microscopes or automatic analyzers to detect abnormalities or diseases in body fluids
- Volunteered to fill in at two other Mayo Clinic locations for three months each, including New York, when there was a shortage of medical lab technicians during the height of COVID-19

Medical Laboratory Technician

Southda/e Pediatric Hospital, Edina, MN (June 2014- September 2019

- Conducted pediatric lab tests in phlebotomy, chemistry, hematology, serology, and urine analysis; collected DMA specimens
- Participated in 22 health fairs for community outreach by performing free lab tests
- Earned a reputation for consistent test validity and rigorous attention to detail
- Completed assigned phlebotomy procedures for 40% of patients in a 500-bed medical facility

Clinical Laboratory Technician

Memorial Blood Centers, Saint Paul, MN j July 2010- May 2014

- Organized_phlebotomy instruction for 11 lab students and three student interns
- Identified symptoms of a patient who was having a stroke and got them immediate medical support
- Executed automated hematology and coagulation tests as well as manual differential investigations on blood and bodily fluids
- Complete patients' medical histories, including their hematocrit, temperature, and blood pressure levels overtime

Education

Associate of Applied Science in Medical Laboratory Technology Lake Superior College Duluth, MN, 2008

Certifications

 Medical Laboratory Technician, American Society for Clinical Pathology, 2009